Art of Latin America since Independence Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Art of Latin America since Independence Photograph Collection
1966-
VRC 307
Yale University Arts Library
3.24
6 boxes
Collection of 380 black and white mounted and labeled photographs from the exhibition Art of Latin America since Independence, Yale University Art Gallery and The University of Texas Art Museum, 1966. The original exhibition list includes 395 works. Fifteen items lost or missing at time of LSF transfer in 2007. Partially illustrated exhibition catalog included with this collection in Box 1: Author: Catlin, Stanton L. (Stanton Loomis), Title: Art of Latin America since independence, by Stanton Loomis Catlin. Edition: [Rev. ed. Published: New Haven, Conn., Yale University, 1966] Description: xiv, 246 p. 118 plates (part col.) 22 x 23 cm.
Catlin, Stantin L. (Stantin Loomis)
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection of 380 black and white mounted and labeled photographs from the exhibition Art of Latin America since Independence, Yale University Art Gallery and The University of Texas Art Museum, 1966. The original exhibition list includes 395 works. Fifteen items lost or missing at time of LSF transfer in 2007. Partially illustrated exhibition catalog included with this collection in Box 1: Author: Catlin, Stanton L. (Stanton Loomis), Title: Art of Latin America since independence, by Stanton Loomis Catlin. Edition: [Rev. ed. Published: New Haven, Conn., Yale University, 1966] Description: xiv, 246 p. 118 plates (part col.) 22 x 23 cm. The works listed here are arranged alphabetically based on the artist's surname according to the use of his country. Catalogue numbers are giving at the beginning of each entry. In dimensions, height precedes width. Illustrations in catalogue entries. Note that several works of art reproduced in the catalogue are not in the exhibition.
Arrangement
Contents in 6 boxes, photographs arranged in numerical order according to the exhibition catalogue numbers:
• Box 1: Printed exhibition catalog as cited above plus photographs 1-56, missing numbers 19, 20, 43, 44
• Box 2: Photographs 57-135, missing numbers 81, 97, 103, 109
• Box 3: Photographs 136-205
• Box 4: Photographs 206-280, missing number 274
• Box 5: Photographs 281-355, missing numbers 286, 287, 310, 349
• Box 6: Photographs 356-395, missing numbers 359, 362
Art, Latin American; Photographs; Reproductions; Art of Latin America since independence
- 1. Abarca, Agustin (Chile, 1882-l955) (Box 1)
  - Landscape (Paisaje), 1930 (Box 1)
- 2. Abramo, Livio (Brazil, 1903- ) (Box 1)
  - Paraguay, 1962 (Box 1)
- 3. Abularach, Rodolfo (Guatemala, 1933- ) (Box 1)
  - Courtesan (Corteza), 1959 (Box 1)
- 4. Acuña, Luis Alberto (Colombia, 1904- ) (Box 1)
  - Figures (Figuras), 1952 (Box 1)
- 5. Adam, Alberto, after J.D. Dulin (active Buenos Aires, 1867) (Box 1)
  - A Slaughterhouse in the State of La Plata (Un Matadero en los Estados de La Plata) (Box 1)
- 6-8 Alfaro Siqueiros, David (Mexico, 1898- ) (Box 1)
  - Moises Saenz, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Portrait of Amado de la Cueva, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Victims of War, 1975 (Box 1)
- 9. Amador, Manuel E. (Panama, 1869-1952) (Box 1)
  - Portrait of President Manuel Amador G. (Box 1)
- 10. do Amaral, Tarsila (Brazil, active since 1920s) (Box 1)
  - The Negress (Box 1)
- 11. Americo de Figueiredo e melo, Pedro (Italy, 1834-1905) (Box 1)
  - Peace and Concord, 1895 (Box 1)
- 12-13. Amoedo, Rodolfo (Brazil, 1857-1941) (Box 1)
  - Maraba, 1882 (Box 1)
  - Bad News, 1895 (Box 1)
- 14. Anonymous (Colombia) (Box 1)
  - La Pola Goes to the Gallows, ca. 1823 (Box 1)
- 15. Anonymous (Mexico) (Box 1)
  - Politcal Farse (Box 1)
- 16. Anonymous (Xalapan, Mexico) (Box 1)
  - Portrait of Miguel Perez Amador (Box 1)
- 17. Anonymous (Mexico) (Box 1)
  - Solemn and Peaceful Entrance of the Trigarantine Army (Box 1)
- 18. Anonymous (Peru) (Box 1)
  - Fruit Market (Box 1)
- 19. Anonymous (Peru) (Box 1)
  - Fruit Seller (Missing, 2007) (Box 1)
- 20. Anonymous (Peru) (Box 1)
  - Piquanteria, ca. 1810 (Missing, 2007) (Box 1)
- 21. Anonymous (Peru) (Box 1)
  - Square of Lima (Box 1)
- 22. Anonymous (Uruguay) (Box 1)
  - Battle of Sarandi in 1825 (Box 1)
- 23. Antunez, Nemesio (Chile, 1918- ) (Box 1)
  - Composition: Sun, 1965 (Box 1)
- 24. Arnal, Enrique (Bolivia, 1932- ) (Box 1)
  - Tambo, 1960 (Box 1)
- 25. Arnout, after Nebel, Karl (latter b. Germany, 1805-1855 (Box 1)
  - Interior of Mexico (Box 1)
- 26-27. Arrieta, Jose Agustin (Mexico, 1802-1879) (Box 1)
  - Market Scene: The Surprise (Box 1)
  - Still Life (Box 1)
- 28. Assler, Federico (Chile, 1929- ) (Box 1)
  - Florescence (Box 1)
- 29. Baca-Flor, Carlos (Peru, 1867-1941 (Box 1)
  - Couple, 1900 (Box 1)
- 30. Bacle, Cesar hipolito (Argentine, b. Switzerland, 1794-1838) (Box 1)
  - Lady of Buenos Aires, Ball Custome, 1834-1835 (Box 1)
- 31-32. Barradas, Rafael Perez (Uruguay, 1890-1928) (Box 1)
  - All at 0.65 (Box 1)
  - Miller from aragon (Box 1)
- 33. Barreda, Ernesto (Chilean, b. France, 1927- ) (Box 1)
  - Embrasure, 1964 (Box 1)
- 34-35. Baz, Ignacio (Argentina, 1826-1887) (Box 1)
  - Gen. Juan Manuel de Rosas (Box 1)
  - Gen. Juan Facundo Quiroga (Box 1)
- 36. Bermudez, Jose Ignacio (Cuba, 1922- ) (Box 1)
  - Microflora, 1956 (Box 1)
- 37-38. Berni, Antonio (Argentina, 1905- ) (Box 1)
  - The Bull Fighter, 1964 (Box 1)
  - The Family, 1957 (Box 1)
- 39. Besnes e Yrigoyen, Juan Manuel (Spain, 1788-1865) (Box 1)
  - The Priest, Docto Perez Castellano (Box 1)
- 40-42. Blanes, Juan Manuel (Uruguay, 1830-1901) (Box 1)
  - Review of the army of Gen. Oribe, 1851 (Box 1)
  - The Association of Gen. Benancio Flores (Box 1)
  - The Two Ways (Box 1)
- 43. Blanes Viale, Pedro (Uruguay, 1879-1926) (Box 1)
  - Palma de Mallorca (Missing, 2007) (Box 1)
- 44. Boari, Adamo (Italian, active in Mexico, 1903-1911) (Box 1)
  - Palacio de Bellas Artes, Mexico, D.F. 1904-1934 (Missing, 2007) (Box 1)
- 45. Boggio, Emilio (Venezuela, 1857-1920) (Box 1)
  - Landscape with Bridge (Box 1)
- 46. Bonatti, Eduardo (Chile, contemporary) (Box 1)
  - Crucifixion (Box 1)
- 47. Bondat (Cuba, 19th century) (Box 1)
  - Battle of Pacocha, 1877 (Box 1)
- 48. Borda, Arturo (Bolivia, 1883-1955) (Box 1)
  - Leonor Gozalvez y Jose Borda (Box 1)
- 49. Botero, Fernando (Colombia, 1932- ) (Box 1)
  - Our Lady of Fatima, 1963 (Box 1)
- 50. Bru, Roser (Spain, 1923- ) (Box 1)
  - The Infinite Life, 1964 (Box 1)
- 51-53. Burchard, Pablo (Chile, 1873-1960) (Box 1)
  - Landscape, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Owls (Box 1)
  - Dandelion, 1940 (Box 1)
- 54. Burchard, Pablo A. (Chile, 1919- ) (Box 1)
  - Sketch for Mural Painting, Cinema Huerfanos (Box 1)
- 55-56. Burchard Haberle, Teodoro (Chile, 19th century) (Box 1)
  - Elevation of San Salvador a la Calle de los Huerfanos, Santiago de Chile, 1874 (Box 1)
  - Longitudinal Section of San Salvador a la Calle de los Huerfanos, Santiago de Chile, 1874 (Box 1)
- 57. Burle Marx, Roberto (Brazil, 1909- ) (Box 2)
  - Detail No. 5 of Plan for Quadricentennial Gardens, Ibiripuera Park, Sao Paulo, 1953 (Box 2)
- 58. Burle Marx, Roberto; Stoddart, J. Godfrey; Tabora, Fernando (contemporary) (Box 2)
  - Eastern Park -- General Plan of Reforestation, Caracas, 1964 (Box 2)
- 59. Butler, Horacio (Argentina, 1897- ) (Box 2)
  - The Farewell, 1937 (Box 2)
- 60. Cabre, Manuel (Venezuela, 1890- ) (Box 2)
  - Landscape of the Lake, 1947 (Box 2)
- 61-63. Cabrera, Francisco (Guatemala, 1781-1845) (Box 2)
  - Doña Teresa Alvora, Marquesa Viuda de Sinibaldi, ca. 1815 (Box 2)
  - Gobernador General Don Jose Bustamante y Guerra (Box 2)
  - Self-Portrait, ca. 1840 (Box 2)
- 64. Calder, Alexander (U.S.A., 1896- ) (Box 2)
  - Design for Ceiling of the Auditorium of the Central University of Venezuela, ca. 1952 (Box 2)
- 65. Camino Brent, Enrique (Peru, 1909- ca. 1960) (Box 2)
  - De Tinta Bridge, Cuzco, 1937 (Box 2)
- 66. Caride, Miguel P. (Argentina, 1920- ) (Box 2)
  - Configuration (Box 2)
- 67-68. Carreño, Mario (Cuba, 1913- ) (Box 2)
  - Homage to Fra Angelico, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Petrified World, 1965 (Box 2)
- 69. Carril, Delia del (Argentina, active 1950s and 1960s) (Box 2)
  - The Virgins, 1963 (Box 2)
- 70-72. Carvalho, Flavio de (Brazil, 1899- ) (Box 2)
  - From the tragic series " My Dying Mother," No.1, 1947 (Box 2)
  - Portrait of Elsie Houston, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Self-Portrait, 1965 (Box 2)
- 73. Castellanos, Julio (Mexico, 1905-1947) (Box 2)
  - The Angel Kidnappers, 1943 (Box 2)
- 74. Castillo, Jose S. de (Colombia, first half, 19th century) (Box 2)
  - Plaza Mayor de Bogota, ca. 1832 (Box 2)
- 75. Castillo, Teofilo (Peru, 1857-1922) (Box 2)
  - Procession, 1917 (Box 2)
- 76. Castro-Cid, Enrique (Chile, 1937- ) (Box 2)
  - Poetical Information, 1963 (Box 2)
- 77-78. Catherwood, Frederick (England, 1799-1854) (Box 2)
  - The Well at Bolochen, Yucatan, 1843 (Box 2)
  - General View of Las Monjas at Uxmal (Box 2)
- 79-81. Cavalcanti, Emiliano di (Brazil, 1897- ) (Box 2)
  - Drawing, 1941 (Box 2)
  - Fisherman, 1942 (Box 2)
  - Five Young Ladies from Guarantingueta, 1930 (Missing, 2007) (Box 2)
- 82. Challamel, Jules Robert (France, 1813- ?), after Lauvergne, Berthelemy (France, 1805-1871) (Box 2)
  - Cathedral of Guayaquil (Box 2)
- 83. Chambelland, Simone (France, presently active in Chile) (Box 2)
  - Litomorfosis I (Box 2)
- 84. Charon, Louis-Francois (France, 1783- after 1831), after Martiner (French?) (Box 2)
  - Simon Bolivar (Box 2)
- 85. Chiappini, J. (Haiti, 1922- ) (Box 2)
  - Portrait of Toussaint L'Ouverture, 1941 (Box 2)
- 86. Clark, Ligia (Brazil, 1920- ) (Box 2)
  - Contra-Relievo Number 2, 1960? (Box 2)
- 87. Clausell, Joaquin (Mexico, 1866-1935) (Box 2)
  - Trees (Box 2)
- 88. Codesido, Julia (Peru, 1892- ) (Box 2)
  - The Andes, 1965? (Box 2)
- 89. Cordero, Juan (Mexico, 1824-1884) (Box 2)
  - The Sculptors Perez and Valero, 1867 (Box 2)
- 90. Coronel, Rafael (Mexico, 1932- ) (Box 2)
  - All Together, 1965 (Box 2)
- 91-92. Covarrubias, Miguel (Mexico, 1904-1957) (Box 2)
  - Project for a Mural for The Museum of Modern Art, New York, 1940 (Box 2)
  - The Lindy Hop, 1936 (Box 2)
- 93. Cravo, Jr. Mario (Brazil, 1923- (Box 2)
  - Studies for Sculpture with Duelling Figures, 1956 (Box 2)
- 94. Cuevas, Jose Luis (Mexico, 1933- ) (Box 2)
  - Self-Portrait with Figures, 1959 (Box 2)
- 95. Cuneo, Perineti, Jose (Uruguay, 1889- ) (Box 2)
  - The Moon over the Ranch, 1934 (Box 2)
- 96. Darondeau, Henri Benoit (France, 1807-1841) (Box 2)
  - Custom for Church and Ball (Box 2)
- 97-98. Debret, Jean Baptiste (France, 1768-1848) (Box 2)
  - Dance of the Savages from the Mission of Saint Joseph (Missing, 2007) (Box 2)
  - Landing of Dona Leopoldina, First Empress of Brazil (Box 2)
- 99. Deira, Ernesto (Argentina, 1928- ) (Box 2)
  - Around Thought A (No. 2), 1964 (Box 2)
- 100. Delhez, Victor (Argentine, b. Belgium, 1901- ) (Box 2)
  - Babilonia,1961 (Box 2)
- 101. Della Valle, Angel (Argentina, 1852-1903) (Box 2)
  - The Return from the Raid, 1892 (Box 2)
- 102. Democrito II (Argentina, 2nd half of 19rh century) (Box 2)
  - Don Quixote, 1891 (Box 2)
- 103. Descalzi, Cayetano (Italy, active Argentina after 1830) (Box 2)
  - Lady of Buenos Aires in front of the Mirror, 1845 (Missing, 2007) (Box 2)
- 104-107. D'Hastrel, Adolphe (France, 1805-1870) (Box 2)
  - Market Scene (Box 2)
  - Porter (Box 2)
  - Rooftops of Montevideo, 1840 (Box 2)
  - The Ruins of the Citadel, 1840 (Box 2)
- 108. Dosamantes, Francisco (Mexico, 1911- ) (Box 2)
  - The Soldier, ca. 1940 (Box 2)
- 109. Doudtchitzky, Dinora (Chilean, b. Ukraine, 1914- ) (Box 2)
  - Engraving I, 1964 (Missing, 2007) (Box 2)
- 110. Doumic, N. (Argentina, active 1844) (Box 2)
  - Soldiers of the Army of Oribe (Box 2)
- 111. Dutary, Alberto (Panama, 1932- ) (Box 2)
  - Tenderness, 1961 (Box 2)
- 112. Egerton, Daniel Thomas (England, ? - 1842) (Box 2)
  - Real del Monte, 1840 (Box 2)
- 113. Escalante, Constantino (Mexico, 1836-1868) (Box 2)
  - "...What kind of hats are we going to buy when we have no heads to put them on!" (Box 2)
- 114. Espinosa, Jose Maria (Colombia, 1796-1883) (Box 2)
  - Store of the Rooster, 1855? (Box 2)
- 115. Estrada, Jose Maria (Mexico, active ca. 1830-1860) (Box 2)
  - Boy with Hat (Box 2)
- 116-118. Fader, Fernando (Argentina, 1882-1935) (Box 2)
  - The Morning -- From the Series "The Life of a Day", 1917 (Box 2)
  - Shawls from Manila (Box 2)
  - Self-Portrait (Box 2)
- 119-120. Faz, Carlos (Chile, 1931-1953) (Box 2)
  - Funeral (Box 2)
  - Stick Roast, 1952 (Box 2)
- 121-122. Fernandez Muro, Jose Antonio (Spain, 1920- ) (Box 2)
  - Flag, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Painting (Box 2)
- 123. Fierro, Panco (Peru, 1803-1879) (Box 2)
  - Procession (Box 2)
- 124-125. Figari, Pedro (Uruguayan, b. Argentina, 1861-1938) (Box 2)
  - Barracks Women, 1922 (Box 2)
  - Sharp Tongue (Box 2)
- 126. Figueroa, Jose Luis (Mexico, active Guadalajara ca. 1910-1940) (Box 2)
  - Earthly Paradise (Box 2)
- 127. Fisquet, Theodore (France, 1813-1890) (Box 2)
  - Humble Dwellings by the Sea -- Valparaiso, 1839 (Box 2)
- 128. Forte, Vicente (Argentina, 1912- ) (Box 2)
  - Totem, 1965 (Box 2)
- 129. Fossa, Juan (Argentina, active ca. 1830-1850) (Box 2)
  - Scene of the Civil War (Box 2)
- 130. Frasconi, Antonio (Uruguayan, b. Argentina, 1919- ) (Box 2)
  - Mother and Child, 1947 (Box 2)
- 131. Gallino, Cayetano (Italy, 1804-1884) (Box 2)
  - Portrait of Don Domingo Gonzalez (Box 2)
- 132. Gamarra, Jose (Uruguay, 1934- ) (Box 2)
  - Painting, 1963 (Box 2)
- 133. Garay, Epifanio (Colombia, 1849-1903) (Box 2)
  - Portrait of a Lady, 1893 (Box 2)
- 134. Garcia del Molino, Fernando (Chile, 1813-1899) (Box 2)
  - Portrait of a Lady (Box 2)
- 135. Gego (Venezuelan, b. Germany, 1912- ) (Box 2)
  - Vertical Engraving, 1963 (Box 2)
- 136. Gerzo, Gunther (Mexico, 1915- ) (Box 3)
  - Mythological Peronage, 1964 (Box 3)
- 137-139. Gil de Castro, Jose (Peru, ? - 1841?) (Box 3)
  - Portrait of Bolivar, 1823 (Box 3)
  - Portrait of Gen. Jose de San Martin, 1818 (Box 3)
  - The Martyr Olaya, 1823 (Box 3)
- 140-141. Goeldi, Oswaldo (Brazil, 1895-1961) (Box 3)
  - Horseman, ca. 1942 (Box 3)
  - Old Age (Box 3)
- 142. Goitia, Francisco (Mexico, 1886-1960) (Box 3)
  - Self-Portrait (Box 3)
- 143. Gomez Cornet, Ramon (Argentina, 1898-1964) (Box 3)
  - Doll, 1931 (Box 3)
- 144. Gomez-Quiroz, Juan (Chile, 1939- ) (Box 3)
  - Description of a Vehicle to Hunt Stars, 1965 (Box 3)
- 145-146. Gonzalez, Carlos (Uruguay, 1905- ) (Box 3)
  - Gauchos, 1937 (Box 3)
  - The Death of Martin Aquino, 1943 (Box 3)
- 147-148. Gonzalez, Jaime (Chile, 1943- ) (Box 3)
  - Cover I for "Altazor" of Vicente Huidobro, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Illustration for "Exterior" of Vicente Huidobro, 196 (Box 3)
- 149. Gonzalez, Juan Francisco (Chile, 1853-1933) (Box 3)
  - Nude, 1925 (Box 3)
- 150-151. Gonzalez G., Fernando; called Zigo (Guatemala, 1894- ) (Box 3)
  - Canon Jose Matias Delgado, 1939 (Box 3)
  - General Justo Rufino Barrios y Francisco Morazon (Box 3)
- 152. Gordon, Arturo (Chile, 1883-1944) (Box 3)
  - The Drunks (Box 3)
- 153. Grandjean de Montigny, August Henri Victor (France, 1776-1850) (Box 3)
  - Plan for the Exchange Building, Rio de Janeiro (Box 3)
- 154. Grashof, Frederico Otto (Prussia, 1812-1876) (Box 3)
  - Cathedral of Montevideo, 1853 (Box 3)
- 155. Grassmann, Marcelo (Brazil, 1925- ) (Box 3)
  - Untitled, 1961 (Box 3)
- 156. Grau, Enrique (Colombia, 1920- ) (Box 3)
  - La Cayetana, 1962 (Box 3)
- 157-158. Grau, Ricardo (Peruvian, b. France, 1908- ) (Box 3)
  - Portrait of a Woman (Box 3)
  - Untitled, 1964? (Box 3)
- 159. Greco, Alberto (Argentina, 1931- ) (Box 3)
  - Painting - Man (Box 3)
- 160. Grilo, Sarah (Argentina, 1921- ) (Box 3)
  - Painting, 1958 (Box 3)
- 161-162. Guayasamin, Oswaldo (Ecuador, 1919- ) (Box 3)
  - Fatigue, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Portrait of Jose Gabriel Navarro, 1942 (Box 3)
- 163-165. Guerrero, Agustin (Ecuador, 1820-1898) (Box 3)
  - Against Such Weapons There's No Defense, 1855 (Box 3)
  - Freedom of the Press, 1855 (Box 3)
  - The Dance of San Juan in Otavalo, 1857 (Box 3)
- 166. Guerrero, Jose E. (Ecuador, 1905- ) (Box 3)
  - Mama Cuchara, 1948 (Box 3)
- 167. Gurvich, Jose (Lithuania, 1927- ) (Box 3)
  - Plaster relief (Box 3)
- 168. Hanne Gallo, Pedro (Colombia, 1930- ) (Box 3)
  - Maternity, 1962 (Box 3)
- 169. Heath, William (England, 1795-1840) (Box 3)
  - Attack on Montevideo (Box 3)
- 170. Herran, Alvaro (Colombia, 1937- ) (Box 3)
  - Painting, 1962 (Box 3)
- 171. Herran, Saturnino (MExico, 1887-1918) (Box 3)
  - The Christ of the Pomegranates (Box 3)
- 172. Herrera Toro, Antonio (Venezuela, 1856-1914) (Box 3)
  - Portrait of a Woman, 1883 (Box 3)
- 173.Hlito, Alfredo (Argentina, 1923- ) (Box 3)
  - Work, 1959 (Box 3)
- 174. Imana Garron, Gil (Bolivia, 1933- ) (Box 3)
  - Patio, 164 (Box 3)
- 175. Iriarte Hesiquio, after Pedro Gualdi (Mexico, 19th century) (Box 3)
  - View of the Panorama fo Mexico City from the Tower of San Agustin (Box 3)
- 176. Jimeno y Planes, Rafael (Spain, 1761-1825) (Box 3)
  - Portrait of Don Manuel Tolsa (Box 3)
- 177. Kingman Riofrio, Eduardo (Ecuador, 1913- ) (Box 3)
  - Los Guandos, 1941 (Box 3)
- 178. Kraft, Guillermo (Germany, 1839-1893), after Emilio Landini (Box 3)
  - Gran Theater of the Opera (Box 3)
- 179-180. Kratzenstein, Rodolfo (Active Argerntina, 1822-1885) (Box 3)
  - German Evangelical Church (Box 3)
  - Sacrifice of Camila O'Gorman and the Priest Gutierrez (Box 3)
- 181-182. Lam, Wilfredo (Cuba, 1902- ) (Box 3)
  - Figures in Black and White, 1954 (Box 3)
  - Still Life, 1923 (Box 3)
- 183. Lamonica, Roberto de (Brazil, 1933- ) (Box 3)
  - Engraving (Box 3)
- 184. La Placa, Alfredo (Bolivia, 1929- ) (Box 3)
  - Abstraction, 1960 (Box 3)
- 185. Lara Centellas, Hugo (Bolivia, 1932- ) (Box 3)
  - Sleeping Figures, 1960 (Box 3)
- 186. Lasansky, Mauricio (Argentina, 1914- ) (Box 3)
  - Dinner, 1937 (Box 3)
- 187. Lee, Wesley Duke (Brazil, 1931- ) (Box 3)
  - Porta Factum, 1965 (Box 3)
- 188. Leger Fernand (France, 1881-1955) (Box 3)
  - Design for Mural for the Central University of Caracas, 1952 (Box 3)
- 189. Lepori (?) (Italy, 19th century) (Box 3)
  - Pictorial Design for Liberty Monument Project (Box 3)
- 190. Leticia, Ana (Brazil, 1929- ) (Box 3)
  - Composition in black and Terra-cotta, 1962 (Box 3)
- 191. Leufert, Gerd (Latvia, 1914- ) (Box 3)
  - Union Square 18, 1964 (Box 3)
- 192. Loballuz (Mexico, 19th century) (Box 3)
  - Stagecoach Hold-up (Box 3)
- 193. Lopez, Candido (Argentina, 1840-1902) (Box 3)
  - Landing of the Argentine Army in front of the Trenches of Curuzu, 1891 (Box 3)
- 194. Lovera, Juan (Venezuela, 1778 ? -1841) (Box 3)
  - Licenciado Francisco Antonio Paul-Coto, ca. 1820 (Box 3)
- 195. Luque, Angel (Venezuelan (Box 3)
  - One Has to Put Color into It, 1964 (Box 3)
- 196. Lynch, Alberto (Chile, 1851- ?) (Box 3)
  - Reclining Lady (Box 3)
- 197. Mabe, Manabu (Brazil, 1924- ) (Box 3)
  - Conquest of the Circle, 1963 (Box 3)
- 198. Maccio, Romulo (Argentina, 1931- ) (Box 3)
  - To Live a Little Each Day (Box 3)
- 199. Margariños, Victor (Argentina, 1924- ) (Box 3)
  - Pintura, 1964 (Box 3)
- 200. Maldonado, Tomas (Argentina, 1922- ) (Box 3)
  - From a Sector (Box 3)
- 201. Maldonado Thibault, G. (Panama, contemporary) (Box 3)
  - The Heroes, 1961 (Box 3)
- 202. Malfatti, Anita (Brazil, 1896- ) (Box 3)
  - Mario de Andrade, 1922 (Box 3)
- 203. Malharro, Martin A. (Argentina, 1865-1911) (Box 3)
  - The Trees (Box 3)
- 204. Monsalvas, Juan (Ecuador, 1840-1906) (Box 3)
  - Four Scenes from Life in QUito, 1865 (Box 3)
- 205 Mariaca Arguedas, Antonio (Bolivia, 1929- ) (Box 3)
  - Lady of the Lake (Box 3)
- 206. Marisol Escobar (Venezuelan, b. Paris, 1930- ) (Box 4)
  - Untitled, 1960 (Box 4)
- 207-209. Mark, Eduardo Walhouse (British, b. Spain, 1817-1895) (Box 4)
  - Main Square - Bogota, 1846 (Box 4)
  - Bridge over the Guali (Box 4)
  - Girl of Guaduas in Sunday Dress, 1846 (Box 4)
- 210. Martens, Conrad (England, 1801-1871) (Box 4)
  - Picnic near Montevideo (Box 4)
- 211. Martinez, Pedro Luis (Cuba, 1910- ) (Box 4)
  - Composition 13, 1957 (Box 4)
- 212. Martins, Aldemir (Brazil, 1922- ) (Box 4)
  - Woman, 1961 (Box 4)
- 213-214. Matta Echaurren, Sebastian Antonio (Chile, 1912- ) (Box 4)
  - Birth of America (Box 4)
  - Condors and Carrion, 1941 (Box 4)
- 215-218. Mendez, Leopoldo (Mexico, 1903- ) (Box 4)
  - The Great Entrance, from Melodic Incidents of the Irrational World, 1944-1945 (Box 4)
  - Vision, 1945 (Box 4)
  - All the Land for the Peasants (Box 4)
  - The Social Gathering (Box 4)
- 219-221. Merida, Carlos (Guatemala, 1891- ) (Box 4)
  - Landscape of Paris, 1910 (Box 4)
  - Four Sketches for a Ceramic Mural, 1963-1965 (Box 4)
  - Urban Landscape, No. 1, 1956 (Box 4)
- 222. Meza, Guillermo (Mexico, 1917- ) (Box 4)
  - Polyphenus, 1941 (Box 4)
- 223. Michelena, Arturo (Venezuela, 1863-1898) (Box 4)
  - Sick Child, 1886 (Box 4)
- 224. Milan, Raul (Cuba, 1914- ) (Box 4)
  - Untitled, 1960 (Box 4)
- 225. Minujin, Mart (Argentina, 1941- ) (Box 4)
  - Erotic Defeat in Technicolor, 1964 (Box 4)
- 226. Monsanto, Antonio Edmundo (Venezuela, 1890-1947 ) (Box 4)
  - Road, 1918? (Box 4)
- 227. Montenegro, Roberto (Mexico, 1885- ) (Box 4)
  - Ego Sum (Box 4)
- 228. Monvoisin, Raymond Quinsac (France, 1790-1870) (Box 4)
  - Portrait of Don Andres Lamas (Box 4)
- 229-230. Morales, Armando (Nicaragua, 1927- ) (Box 4)
  - Nude, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Landscape, 1964 (Box 4)
- 231-232. Morel, Carlos (Argentina, 1813-1894) (Box 4)
  - Calvary Battle (Box 4)
  - Portrait of Señorita Macedonia Escardo, 1839 (Box 4)
- 233. Moulin, Hipolito (active Argentina, 1830s) (Box 4)
  - Lady of Buenos Aires, Promenade Costume, 1834-1835 (Box 4)
- 234. Muller-Lewit, Mario (Ecuador, 1940- ) (Box 4)
  - Painting - Cycle of the Earth, 1962 (Box 4)
- 235. Nebel, Karl (Germany, 1805-1855) (Box 4)
  - The Pyramid of Cholula (Box 4)
- 236. Obregon, Alejandro (Colombia, 1920- ) (Box 4)
  - Carnivorous Flowers (Box 4)
- 237. Odriozola, Fernando (Brazil, b. Spain, 1921- ) (Box 4)
  - Drawing (Box 4)
- 238-244. O'Gorman, Juan (MExico, 1905- ) (Box 4)
  - Memory of Los Remedios, 1943 (Box 4)
  - Project for Fresco mural "History of Michoacan," "Gertrudis Bocanegra" Library, Patzcuaro, Michoacan, Mexico, 1939 (Box 4)
  - Project for primary school, Tamaulipas, Mexico, 1932 (Box 4)
  - Project for secondary school, Tamaulipas, Mexico, 132 (Box 4)
  - Project for Telephone Workers Union Building, Mexico, D.F., 1933 (Box 4)
  - Project for the exterior Mosaic Murals, Library of the University Nacional Autonoma de Mexico, South Wall (Box 4)
  - Projects for Exterior Mosaic Murals of the Universidad Nacional Autonoma de Mexico, East and West Walls (Box 4)
- 262-263. Palliere, Juan Leon (Brazil, 1823-1887) (Box 4)
  - Landscape of the Jungle fo the Argentine Misiones Province, 1864 (Box 4)
  - The Store (Box 4)
- 264. Pardo, Mercedes (Venezuela, 1922- ) (Box 4)
  - Primordial detaille en ustensiles, 1962 (Box 4)
- 265. Paredes, Diogenes (Ecuador, 1910- ) (Box 4)
  - Onions Carriers (Box 4)
- 266. Parsons, G., after Whiting, Daniel Powers (latter, U.S.A., 1808-1892) (Box 4)
  - Valley near Saltillo (Box 4)
- 267. Paternosto, Cesar (Argentina, 1931- ) (Box 4)
  - Climax, 1959 (Box 4)
- 268-270. Pellegrini, Carlos Enrique (Savoy, 1800-1875) (Box 4)
  - Minuet, 1831 (Box 4)
  - Doña Agustina Rozas de Mansilla and Her Son Lucio (Box 4)
  - Don Manuel Bernardino Masculino (Box 4)
- 271-272. Petres, Fray Domingo de (spain, 1759-1811) (Box 4)
  - Longitudinal Section of the Cathedral Church of Santa Fe, Bogota, ca. 1805 (Box 4)
  - Plan and Profile of the Cathedral Church of Santa Fe, Bogota (Box 4)
- 273-274. Pettoruti, Emilio (Argentina, 1892- ) (Box 4)
  - Man with Yellow Flower, 1932 (Box 4)
  - The Quintet, 1927 (Missing, 2007) (Box 4)
- 275. Pinto, Joaquin (Ecuador, 1842-1906) (Box 4)
  - Study of a Bird (Box 4)
- 276. Pisarro, Camille (French, b. St. Thomas, 1850-1903) (Box 4)
  - Landscape with Figures (Box 4)